Shailesh Modi, BSC, MLW, MBA, LLB

(Mobile) +91-9925021121 Email: skmodi204208@gmail.com

Senior HR Management Professional as Head HR-IR/CHRO/VP HR-IR/GM HR-IR

Brief Profile: -

Shailesh is Master of Labour Welfare, MBA and LLB having more than 22 years' experience in Strategic Human Resource, Organizational Development, Competency Assessment, SAP HR, Change Management, Industrial Relation, Legal Matters, Union Management, Long Term Settlement, Labour Laws, Court Matters, Labour Welfare, General Administration, Commercial and Project Management.

Professional Achievements: -

During my career, we signed <u>Long Term Settlements</u> with WIN WIN approach with increasing in productivity by way of Incentives and other measures. We have sorted out more than <u>150 labour cases</u> in the different courts. Streamlining the Contract Management System. We have carried out Organizational Development Initiative with Thomas Profiling and Assessment Centre of 300 employees, Introduced Online Monthly Performance Appraisal System, Implemented Online HR ESS Fiori – Digitization of HR processes, revoke of contract labour prohibition and Worked as Change Agent in the organization which resulted HR is part of Board Room, and the company came out from BIFR Sick unit to a Profit-Making Company.

During my leadership, Windsor Machines got Outstanding Industrial Relation Award (First Runner Up) from AIOE for the year 2015-16 and National Award for Strong Commitment in Employee Relations 2017 by Employers Federation of India. I was selected for ERHG Programme organized by AOTS, Tokyo, Japan from 15th January to 26th January'2018.

Education Qualification: -

- B.Sc. with Statistics (1996) Gold Medal in North Gujarat University
- Master of Labour Welfare (1998) Second Position in Gujarat University
- LLB from Gujarat University (2020)
- Master of Business Administration (2007) Correspondences
- Proficient in Competency Mapping by T V Rao Learning Institute (2007)
- Lead Auditor ISO 9001 by BVQI (2012)

Professional Experience Summary: -

TORRENT POWER LIMITED, Ahmedabad

7th October'2019 to Continue

Assistant General Manager HR

(Torrent Power is one of the leading brands in the Indian power sector, promoted by the Rs. 21500 Crore Torrent Group – committed to its mission of transforming life by serving two of the most critical needs - healthcare and power. It is an integrated power utility and is one of the largest private sector players in India having interests in power generation, transmission, distribution and manufacturing and supply of power cables. Heading Zonal HR Function in Ahmedabad and Gandhinagar license areas. Responsible for HR Operation, Industrial Relation, Legal Matters, Liaison of 3000 company employees and 8000 Contract Labours.

WINDSOR MACHINES LIMITED, Ahmedabad

17th August'2009 to 5th October 2019

Chief Human Resource Officer

(Windsor Machines Limited is one of the select few companies in India, which serves and supports the varied needs of plastic processing industry across 65 countries (an impressive installation base of over 20000 machines) with cutting edge product design and latest technology, wherein we are

engaged in manufacturing Injection Moulding, Pipe Extrusion and Blown Films machineries, all under one roof. Worked as CHRO and was part of top management team. I was responsible for HR and Commercial function of two factories - Injection Moulding Division— Chhatral & Extrusion, Blow Moulding Division- Vatva)

MIDCO LIMITED, Vatva – Ahmedabad

15th January'2001 to 26th June'09

Sr. Manager HR

(Midco Limited operates as a manufacturer of dispensing equipment. The Company provides petroleum dispensing equipment, high-lift centrifugal pumps, embedded systems development, field maintenance, LPG dispensers, and after sales services. Midco serves customers worldwide. I was heading HR Function of two factories, Midco Limited and Hexagon Midco India Private Limited).

M/s Navin Associates – Ahmedabad Personnel Assistant May'2000 to October 2000

Reliance Petroleum Ltd. - Jamnagar Personnel & IR Coordinator

9th Nov'1998 to 8th Nov.' 1999

Professional Expertise:

- Built up the entire set up of HR & Admin systems, processes and designed the organization structure to effectively to cater the business needs by effective Manpower Planning (MPP).
- Designing Job Description (JD) across the organization and restructure the entire Organogram to optimize the requirement starting from top to bottom level.
- Carried out competency-based recruitment of talent within predefined turnaround time on a continuous basis by engaging best Talent from the market.
- Designed induction and onboarding module for candidates joining in the organization.
- Designing & implementing HR Policy in the organization.
- Designing and managing Salary Payroll. Framed the tax effective Salary structure in view of Budget and guideline.
- Participated in Compensation & Benefit survey of reputed agencies/companies.
- Implemented a structured talent management module and system reinforcing a performance driven culture through extensive usage of Assessment Centers, Thomas Profiling, TST, MIRD analysis and restructuring the KRA based goal setting PMS to achieve straight line directed goal objectives from top to bottom level.
- Initiated HR concepts like Succession Planning, Career Planning, Career Enhancement Program, Potential category analysis, Scientific increment calculator.
- Created an engaged workforce through an engagement initiatives, objective and transparent Rewards & Recognition program and aggressively driven a value-based performance system in the organization.
- Developed in-house trainers from the workers for continuous Training & Development activities and organizational development initiatives by the workmen.
- Evolved HR plan through a Participative Approach with the Trade unions enabling a paradigm shift from IR to HR approach to resolve issues & disputes with best of the Statutory Requirement.
- Disciplinary action, Initiation & monitoring disciplinary proceedings, domestic inquiries & charge sheet etc.
- Handled Unions, Wage settlement Long Term & Short Term, Strike, Lock-out, Grievance Committee, SHP, Collective Bargaining.
- Set up the climate for Negotiations & executed productivity linked Long Term Wage Settlements with Trade Unions.
- Ensured out of Court Settlements for most of the pending Conciliation/Tribunal Cases.
- Expeditiously closed long pending disputes and Grievances through a collaborative approach with the unions.

- Personally attended court cases in Labour Court, Industrial Tribunal, High Court of Gujarat and Mumbai and Supreme Court of India.
- Personnel & Administration activities viz. Leave Records, Wage & Salary Admin., Tendering Process, Gardening, Transportation, Township Mngt., Accommodation, House Keeping, administration, Security etc.
- Effectively managed all issues related to Contract Labour.
- Handling 8000 Contract Labour Workforce. Implemented online Contract Management System.
- Ensured standardization of all legal compliance, legal and statutory matters of all applicable labour laws.
- Actively involved in Counselling and Mentoring activity.
- Handling CSR activities and compliance. Identifying various CSR projects in the predefined areas viz. Medical, Educational, Specially Abled and Youth recreation.
- Actively involved in the implementation of Skill Development Program An initiative by Govt. of India under the roof of Make in India Concept.
- Obtain/Renew/Amendment/Registration of Licenses under Factories Act, Contract Labor Act, Shops & Establishment Act, Weights & Measures Act, Ahmedabad Municipal Corporation, Electricity Department, Explosive Department, DIC, NSIC, SISI, DGS &D, BIS, GPCB etc.,
- Involved in commercial activity line non-Bom items, one time purchase, negotiating with Civil Contractors/Fabricators for New/Extension work in the organization.
- Integrated Management System (ISO, EMS and OHSAS)

Major Training/Seminars attended: -

- ERHG Programme by AOTS at Tokyo Japan in Jan'2018
- Industrial Relation Conferences by CII's
- HR Conclave by Ahmedabad Management Association
- Sustainable Business Competitiveness through Employee Relations by EFI
- HR Summit HR Conundrum by HR Milestone
- Sexual Harassment Workshop by Labour Law Institute
- Labour Law Conference by AIMA
- Human Resource (HR) Audit by Academy of Human Resource Development
- Performance Management System by Indo American Chamber of Commerce
- HR Conclave by Gujarat Employers Organization
- HR Conference by CII Vadodara

Membership with Institutes: -

- Member of Quality Circle Forum of India
- Member of CII Industrial Relation Committee (CII Gujarat Chapter)

 Conducted two IR/HR Conferences in Ahmedabad
- Membership of AOTS HIDA Alumni Gujarat Chapter
- Core committee member of HR Milestone Group in Ahmedabad
- Executive Member of Chhatral Industries Association 2014-15
- Executive Member of Vatva Industrial Association in 2012-13

Personal Details: -

- DOB 22/11/1974
- Marital Status Married, wife Housewife, one son studying in MBBS
- Residential Address B 204, Stavan Avisha, Behind Seema Hall, Satellite, Ahmedabad
- Passport with USA Visitor Visa, Countries Visited Germany, Netherland, Japan, UAE and USA